<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>mxplusb</title>
    <link>http://example.org/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on mxplusb</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright 2017 Mike Lloyd</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2017 15:25:58 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://example.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2017 15:25:58 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;First, let&amp;rsquo;s start this off with a short introduction. My name is Mike Lloyd, and I am currently a Senior Solutions Architect with &lt;a href=&#34;https://pivotal.io/&#34;&gt;Pivotal Software, Inc&lt;/a&gt;. I would like to first start off by stating this blog does not, in any way, represent &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.delltechnologies.com/en-us/index.htm&#34;&gt;Dell Technologies&amp;rsquo;&lt;/a&gt; (or any of their holdings) opinions , their business practices, their IP, and any content contained in this blog, regardless of whichever post, is of my own opinion and of my own devices. You will likely see many posts regarding integrations with products derived from their IP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disclaimer: You may or may not stumble upon various instances of profane language. I feel being able to speak my mind honestly (which is usually just stream of consciousness) is important.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As far as what you&amp;rsquo;ll see on this blog, you&amp;rsquo;ll see integrations for enterprise software, video games (&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;yay!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;), prolly some data analysis, and whatever else floats my boat. If you saw the tag line, you&amp;rsquo;ll notice that I really just like to fiddle around with little bits of code, here and there. I have a terrible tendency to not finish large personal projects because I get distracted, so I really like to work on small little things, just so I can keep my own sanity by feeling good about something I was able to finish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is said that if you know your enemies and know yourself, you will not be imperiled in a hundred battles; if you do not know your enemies but do know yourself, you will win one and lose one; if you do not know your enemies nor yourself, you will be imperiled in every single battle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;cite&gt;Sun Tzu&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hence why I like to fiddle with little bits of code and why I don&amp;rsquo;t really like to do large projects in my personal life. Ironically, I have a great sense of commitment for work. I do love pop culture, and you will see many pop culture references across my posts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy Reading!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fee free to reach out to me if you have any questions!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For humans, translate 1337 to regular:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;k3v1n dot m1ch@3l dot ll0yd at gmail dot com&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who, What, Why, and How</title>
      <link>http://example.org/blog/the-making-of-this/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jan 2017 15:15:02 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/blog/the-making-of-this/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-new-hope&#34;&gt;A New Hope&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m terrible at blogging, there is no doubt about it. I have struggled for many years with it, but now I have hit a point in my career where having a personal blog is recommended, and it&amp;rsquo;s best for me to suck it up and maintain one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With that in mind, I figured I would go into some details on how this blog is built. Who, I guess is irrelevant (just read my about page!), so I&amp;rsquo;ll talk about What I used, Why I used it, and How I use it. When I titled this, I was going to introduce myself, but I ended up moving that to the About page, as well my industry&amp;rsquo;s standard disclaimer of &lt;code&gt;this is mine, not representative of my employer, blah blah blah&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-empire-strikes-back&#34;&gt;The Empire Strikes Back&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In regards to what I used, I actually used a static website generator. I have tried using a fully-featured CMS engine, like &lt;a href=&#34;https://wordpress.org/&#34;&gt;WordPress&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/&#34;&gt;Medium&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a href=&#34;https://ghost.org/&#34;&gt;Ghost&lt;/a&gt;. While I thought all of them were pretty spiffy, I felt it was entirely too much for me to cope with. I wanted control, I wanted to host it myself, and I wanted to be able to treat my blog like code. Blogging as Code(&lt;sup&gt;TM&lt;/sup&gt;). I have tried &lt;a href=&#34;https://jekyllrb.com/&#34;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; in the past, and it was alright; it had one major flaw, though: &lt;em&gt;IT IS WRITTEN IN RUBY&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those of you that don&amp;rsquo;t know me, I have a deep set disgust for most things Ruby. While Ruby is fine, and it is interpreted similar to Python, I can&amp;rsquo;t get over the syntax. I feel like I&amp;rsquo;m programming like a child with it&amp;rsquo;s simplistic, expressive language. It&amp;rsquo;s slow, and any form of parallelism or concurrency is just&amp;hellip;challenging.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So Jekyll was out the door, time to search for something I could contribute to, if I ever had the desire. I&amp;rsquo;m a huge fan of Google&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://golang.org&#34;&gt;Go&lt;/a&gt;, so I started looking for something like Jekyll, but in Go. I didn&amp;rsquo;t have to look far, I stumbled across &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt;. Their tag line: &lt;code&gt;Make the Web Fun Again&lt;/code&gt;. Perfect, I like fun. Especially as I&amp;rsquo;m not a UI wizard&amp;hellip;those mystical powers reside with others. Looking into Hugo, I found it was produced by &lt;a href=&#34;http://spf13.com/&#34;&gt;spf13&lt;/a&gt;, who writes one of my favourite command line client interfaces, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/spf13/cobra&#34;&gt;cobra&lt;/a&gt;. I was exceedingly pleased, and I knew he experience would be a fun one, both to learn and to maintain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes We Can.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;cite&gt;Barack Obama&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;return-of-the-jedi&#34;&gt;Return of the Jedi&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I searched long and hard for the right &lt;a href=&#34;http://themes.gohugo.io/&#34;&gt;theme&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;m picky about presentation, and I feel first impressions are the most important. I tried so many different themes, for awhile. After lots of &lt;em&gt;close, but no cigar&lt;/em&gt; tries, I finally settled on this one, &lt;a href=&#34;http://themes.gohugo.io/hugo-theme-cactus-plus/&#34;&gt;Cactus Plus&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s simplistic, fast (all of Hugo is fast, lol), the text is okay, and it&amp;rsquo;s overall, a decent theme. I like the &lt;a href=&#34;https://highlightjs.org/&#34;&gt;Highlight.js&lt;/a&gt; markdown renderer, it produces nice contrast to the white style. This is the Why.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Python:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-python&#34;&gt;from sys import stdout; stdout.write(&amp;quot;See? Looks good.&amp;quot;)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Go:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-go&#34;&gt;package main

import &amp;quot;fmt&amp;quot;

func main() {
    fmt.Println(&amp;quot;See? Still looks good.&amp;quot;)
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;C:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-c&#34;&gt;#include &amp;lt;stdio.h&amp;gt;
int main() {
    printf(&amp;quot;Still going strong.&amp;quot;);
    return 0;
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;C#:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-csharp&#34;&gt;using System;

class Program
{
    static void Main()
    {
        string works = &amp;quot;Man, this highlighter is super awesome.&amp;quot;;
        Console.WriteLine(works);
    }
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I really like it, it&amp;rsquo;s clean. Now, I have highlight.js configured to use the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/bulenkov/Darcula&#34;&gt;Darcula&lt;/a&gt; theme from Konstantin Bulenkov. I use various &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jetbrains.com/&#34;&gt;Jetbrains&lt;/a&gt; editors, and they all use the Darcula theme. I feel it&amp;rsquo;s easier on the eyes. I&amp;rsquo;ll go over how I integrated Hugo with WebStorm in a later post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-force-awakens&#34;&gt;The Force Awakens&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How I made this is pretty simple, I mostly just followed the directions and Read The F***ing Manual. One of my favourite sayings:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Real men don&amp;rsquo;t need instructions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;cite&gt;Tim &amp;ldquo;The Toolman&amp;rdquo; Taylor&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is so unbelievably inaccurate it&amp;rsquo;s laughable, lol. I read manuals all the time. API, vehicle, toaster (oh yes),  and many other manuals. Without manuals, I would be helpless. I would highly recommend reading the &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/overview/introduction/&#34;&gt;Hugo manual&lt;/a&gt; if you want to create your own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s about it, for now. Thanks!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>